Guide to the Department of Electrical Engineering, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Electrical Engineering, Yale University, records
1910-1983
RU 55
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
14.5
The records consist of correspondence, annual reports, financial records, and subject files documenting scholarships and awards, loans and funding, research projects, and personnel of the Yale School of Engineering's Department of Electrical Engineering.
Yale University. School of Engineering
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 23-E (YRG 23-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the School of Engineering.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, annual reports, financial records, and subject files documenting scholarships and awards, loans and funding, research projects, and personnel of the Yale School of Engineering's Department of Electrical Engineering.
Electrical engineering -- Study and teaching; Engineering -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. School of Engineering
- Records, circa 1910-1968; Accession 1970-A-005
  - Accident Reports, 1938-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advanced Products, Inc., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agreements, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Air Conditioning (Carrier), 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Air Raid Material, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Bosch Project, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers (A.I.E.E.) Student Branch, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Awards, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Camp Miscellaneous, 1926-1943 (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
  - Cash slips and notebooks, 1949-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chalk, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Christmas, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cleaning, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Computer data, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, lists and records
    - 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 29 - 30)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 35 - 36)
  - Engineering College Research Council, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Engineers Joint Council, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Equipment - Laboratory, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Faculty minutes, 1938-1961 (Box 2, Folder 40 - 41)
  - Financial records
    - Appropriation ledgers, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 42 - 43)
    - Budgets, 1930-1953 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Contracts and specifications, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Ledger, 1951-1967 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Monthly Staternents
      - 1932-1946 (Box 2, Folder 47 - 48)
      - 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Requisition slips
      - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 52 - 55)
      - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 56 - 58)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - University Treasurer, 1937-1956 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Friden Calculating Machine, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - General Precision Laboratory Research, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Gifts, 1949-1961 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Glove Testing
    - 1944-1961 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 65 - 68)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 69 - 73)
    - 1958-1966 (Box 3, Folder 74 - 78)
  - Godsey, F.W. (Westinghouse), 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Griggs, Henry L., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Heating system - Dunham Laboratory, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Industrial Administration Office, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Institute of Radio Engineers Convention, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - International Business Machine Corporation (IBM), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Interviews
    - 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 88 - 89)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 91 - 92)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 93 - 94)
  - Inventories
    - 1923-38 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - 1941 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - 1947 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - 1949 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - 1950-1963 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - 1952 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - 1955 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - 1955-1968 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - I-T-E Network Analyzer, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Key Records, 1958-1967 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Laboratory Fees, 1933-1956 (Box 4, Folder 106 - 107)
  - Lecture Hall - Dunham Laboratory, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Lincoln Meter Company (Lincoln Arc Welding), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Loans: Equiprnent, 1946-1961 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Maps: Engineering Camp, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Mimeograph material, 1949-1955 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Monroe Calculating machine, undated (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Mottoes, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - National Acadeny of Sciences -- National Research Council, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - National Defense, 1941-1960 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - National Electric Light Association - Course for metermen, 1926-1929 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - National Science Foundation, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Porter, Richard W., 1946-1964 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Provost
    - 1944-1956 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Public Utilities Commission, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Publications, 1948-1958 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Purchasing procedures and stock lists, 1951-1967 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Radar - equipment and installation, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Radio kits (Meissner), 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Radio Lab - instruction books, undated (Box 5, Folder 137 - 138)
  - Receipts, 1939-1950 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Reconstruction Finance Company, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Research projects
    - Bell Telephone Lab
      - Contract and Correspondence, 1959-1965 (Box 5, Folder 141)
      - Monthly Statements, 1954-1964 (Box 5, Folder 142)
      - Progress Reports
        - Nos. 1-3, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 143)
        - Nos. 4-5, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 144)
        - No. 6, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 145)
        - Nos. 7-10, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 146)
        - No. 11, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 147)
        - Nos. 12-15, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 148)
        - Nos. 16-21, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 149)
        - Nos. 22-23, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - General
      - Proposals
        - 1946-1952 (Box 6, Folder 151)
        - 1956 (Box 6, Folder 152)
        - 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 153 - 154)
      - Yearly Wage and Salary Summary, 1946-1958 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - General Dynamics/Electric Boat Research
      - Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 6, Folder 156)
      - Monthly Statements, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 157)
      - Progress Reports
        - Nos. 1-7, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 158)
        - Nos. 8-15, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 159)
        - Nos. 16-19, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 160)
        - No. 20, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 161)
        - Nos. 21-28, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - General Precision Lab - Progress reports, 1954-1958 (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 164)
      - Monthly Statements, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 165)
      - Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Sperry Gyroscope and Company
      - Correspondence and Monthly Statements, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 167)
      - Reports, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Theory of Valuated Information
      - Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 169)
      - Reports, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Room schedules, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Scholarships and Fellowships, 1951-1958 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - American Brake Shoe Foundation, 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Clark, Noyes D. Fellowship, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Coffin, Charles A. Fellowship, 1938-1953 (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Eastman Kodak, Thomas Edison Fellowship, 1940-1963 (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - I-T-E Circuit Breaker Co., International Telephone and Telegraph Corporation, 1957-1963 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Radio Corp. of America (RCA), Research Corp., Sperry Gyroscope, 1946-1958 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Gerard Swope, Transistor Products Inc., University (School of Engineering), 1937-1963 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Alessandro Volta, Westinghouse, 1945-1960 (Box 7, Folder 185 - 186)
  - Security, 1958-1964 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Servo Paper Form, undated (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Sigma Xi, 1962-1965 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Student Schedules and Enrollment, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Superior Electric Company, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Surplus Material, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Surveying instruments, 1935-1956 (Box 7, Folder 193 - 194)
  - Symbols, undated (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - Tax Exemption, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 196)
  - Technical information - Pilot reports, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 197 - 199)
  - Thesis requirements, 1956-1963 (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - Travelling expenses, 1954-1966 (Box 8, Folder 201 - 202)
  - Vari-Typer data, undated (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Woolsey Hall - Public Address System, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 204)
  - Yale Engineering Association, 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Yale University - maps and diagrams, undated (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - RESTRICTED MATERIAL
    Conditions Governing Access
    These records are restricted until Jan 1, 2043.
    - Personnel and Training Grant
      - Department of Health, Education and Welfare
        - Applications, undated (Box 10, Folder 213 - 214)
        - Correspondence and Records, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 215 - 219)
      - Inactive Personne1
        - A-Ba, 1948-1960 (Box 10, Folder 220)
        - Belove, Charles, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 221)
        - Be-Bou, 1946-1964 (Box 10, Folder 222)
        - Bower, John L., 1946-1950 (Box 10, Folder 223)
        - Br-Cap, 1943-1962 (Box 10, Folder 224)
        - Car-Con, 1946-1960 (Box 10, Folder 225)
        - Corey, H.E., 1944-1960 (Box 10, Folder 226)
        - Corr-Ec, 1940-1962 (Box 10, Folder 227)
        - Ei-Fo, 1943-1964 (Box 10, Folder 228)
        - Fr-Ga, 1945-1963 (Box 10, Folder 229)
        - Ge-Gr, 1944-1962 (Box 10, Folder 230)
        - H-J, 1939-1963 (Box 10, Folder 231)
        - K-Le, 1945-1965 (Box 10, Folder 232)
        - Laboratory Assistants, 1947-1965 (Box 11, Folder 233)
        - Ledger, 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 234)
        - Li -Ma, 1945-1964 (Box 11, Folder 235)
        - Me-N, 1947-1963 (Box 11, Folder 236)
        - O-Re, 1946-1964 (Box 11, Folder 237)
        - Rh-She, 1947-1964 (Box 12, Folder 238)
        - Secretaries, 1943-1963 (Box 12, Folder 239)
        - Shi-T, 1939-1960 (Box 12, Folder 240)
        - U-Wag, 1940-1963 (Box 12, Folder 241)
        - Wak-Wo, 1937-1963 (Box 12, Folder 242)
      - Morcus, Stanley, 1955-1960 (Box 12, Folder 243)
      - Graduate Students
        - 1957-1958 (Box 13, Folder 244)
        - 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 245)
        - 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 246)
        - 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 247)
        - 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 248)
- Records, 1949-1981; Accession 1995-A-028
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017
  - Electrical Engineering Faculty Meetings, 1949-1963 (Box 1)
  - Wohlenberg [Dean], 1952-1955 (Box 1)
  - Mendenhill Report on General Education, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Reports on Science at Yale
    - Margenau, 1955? (Box 1)
    - Patterson, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Boell, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Altman, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Young [Dean], 1956-1960 (Box 1)
  - Accreditation [Engineer's Council for Professional Development -- ECPD], 1956-1966 (Box 1)
  - School of Engineering's Objectives, 1957 (Box 1)
  - School of Engineering's Undergraduate Programs, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Krauss Committee, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Robertson Committee, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Chemical Engineering's History -- Dodge [compiled by chairman Dodge], 1960 (Box 1)
  - Dodge [Chairman], 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Deanship Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Zweig [Dean], 1961-1966 (Box 1)
  - Dodge Faculty Questionnaire, 1961 January (Box 1)
  - ECPD Questionnaire [in binder, not folder], 1961 February (Box 1)
  - ECPD-ABET Rules, 1963-1968 (Box 1)
  - Goals Material [includes publications], 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - ECPD Visit, 1966 April (Box 1)
  - Wegener [Chairman], 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - NEACSS Visit [New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools], 1968 February (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Accreditation Committee, 1969 January (Box 1)
  - Manifestos -- Fenn, Phillips, Wegener et al [Professors and Chairman], 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Becton Center Dedication, 1970 (Box 1)
  - ECPD [Accreditation], 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - ECPD Accreditation Questionnaire [in binder, not folder], 1973 (Box 1)
  - ECPD [Accreditation], 1978 (Box 1)
  - FBT [Franz B. Tuteur, Professor], 1979 (Box 1)
  - ECPD [Preliminary Report], 1979 (Box 2)
  - EAS Review [Engineering and Applied Sciences], 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Schultheiss Committee Reports, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Accreditation [ECPD], 1981 (Box 2)
- Records, circa 1942-1983; Accession 1999-A-026
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018
  - Individuals scores ETS (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate program (testing) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Heat regenerators and their low temperature application by Lloyd M. Watson, July 1942 (bound thesis) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Liquefaction of hydrogen (bound thesis) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notes (miscellaneous) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notes on manuscript or dissertation (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brazton cycle refrigerator (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Book on history of thermodynamics (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Thermo properties and book on Phase equilibria of cryogenic systems" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CS 530 digital systems TA answer key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - EE349b: course description, misc. computer printouts, real time programming exercise, Motorola... cross assembler (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - EE348 fall 1983: homework, project assignments, midterm exam, final exam (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - EE348 fall 1983: lecture summaries (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - EE348: planning, class list, TAs (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - EE348: Inventory, sign up, instructions for teaching fellows, course description, lab exercises, homework assignments, midterm exam (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Unfiled Materials: Basic thermodynamic principles and their formulation: table of contents, ch 3-4, ch 4(5) renamed 5 comp/ expand of gases, ch6-10, 12-17, 19, 21,ch4 partial missing pp88-94, ch8 missing pp. 92-95